(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T09:17:41.160058",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
もっと もっと 上がるよ空に
More and more, rising into the sky,
大きな夏の華
A giant summer flower.
君と眺める夏の花
[Song: Flowers We View Together in Summer]
ふらふら歩くよ 楽しい香りに誘われて
Stumbling around, lured by the fun aroma,
からころ響くよ 下駄のどこまでも
Wooden clogs echo all the way, no matter where—
きらきら輝く 屋台の明かりに飛び込んで
Dashing into the sparkling stalls' bright lights,
ぴちぴち跳ね回る 真っ赤なイチゴ飴
Bouncing around, a bright red candy apple.
さあそっと待ってね ずっと待ってた
Come on, wait softly, I've been waiting forever!
ほらね今年も 花火が打ち上がる
Look, fireworks are launching again this year!
さあ祭だ祭だ祭だ わっしょいみんなの出囃子で声出して
Come on, it's a festival! Washhoi! Shout out with everyone's entrance music!
もっともっと上がるよ
It's still, still going up!
花火もテンションも
Fireworks and tension too!
もっと！
More!
きらきらきらめき生きるもの
Dazzlingly, brilliantly shining things
すべてがまぶしくて
All of them are dazzling
しゃくしゃく食べ歩くかき氷り
Walking the streets hand in hand, eating shaved ice!
さあ、ばんばんかばかやれ！
Come on, let's play, ba-ba-bam!
ずっと笑わせて
Make us smile endlessly,
きみの笑顔の花火が打ち上がる
The fireworks of your smile launch up!
楽しいお祭りだ止まるのは嫌！
The fun festival mustn't stop!
下駄も忘れて跳ねるよ
I'll forget my geta sandals and just jump!
もっともっと上がるよ空に！
It's still, still going up into the sky!
大きな夏の花
A huge summer flower!
みんな！今日は最後まで盛り上がろう！
Everyone, let's get excited and soar together!
まだまだ始まったばかり！
It's still just beginning!
最後まで盛り上がっていってね！
Let's get hyped all the way to the end!
とけるよ 一瞬が輝く時間も溶けてゆく
A moment that shines, melting away with you...
君との思い出溶けない 一生消えない宝物
Memories with you that won't melt away, never fading!
流れる光に照らされて
Illuminated in the flowing light,
すべてがまぶしい思い出
All of it is a dazzling memory!
君と眺める夏の花
Gazing at the summer flowers with you...
「最初から君を 好きでいられて 良かった」なんて
"I'm glad I was able to love you from the beginning,"
空に歌うんだ
that's what I'm going to sing to the sky.
よかったなんて
If only I could say that...
あぁ
Ah...
詰め込んだ夢を 打ち上げる場所 探し求めて
Seeking a place where I can jumpstart my packed-in dreams,
この街から出た
I left this town.
震える着信 電源を切った
My phone vibrates with an incoming call, I turned the power off.
燃え出す導火線 誰も止められない
My fuse is burning; no one can stop it.
世界の終わりが 今訪れたとしたら
If the end of the world arrived now,
全部ほっぽって ふたり永遠に一緒になるのにね
Then I would leave everything behind and the two of us would be together forever.
Like a Fire Flower
ぼくが消えちゃわないように
so I won't vanish,
火の粉散らし 夢打ち上げろ
sparks scatter, and my dreams launch themselves upwards.
「最初から君を 好きにならなかったら 良かった」なんて
"I wish I hadn't loved you from the beginning,"
嘘までついて
that's what I went so far as to lie...
あぁ
Ah...
慣れない景色 不自然な笑顔
A view I'm not used to, unnatural smiles.
華やかな祭りとは違ってた
The festival wasn't the showy kind.
繰り返す留守電 「ガンバレ」の声
My voicemail replays a voice saying, "Keep your chin up!"
涙で導火線 消えちゃいそうだよ
My fuse is about to go out from my tears.
宇宙の始まりが あの口付けだとしたら
If the beginning of the universe was that kiss,
星空は ふたり零した奇跡の跡
then the starry sky is the traces of miracles that the two of us shed.
Like a Fire Flower
君が見つけやすいように 雷鳴の如く夢と轟かせ
I'll make my dreams roar like a thunderclap
最初から君を 好きにならなかったら よかったなんて バレてんだろうボクな
so that you'll be able to find them easily.
あぁ
Ah...
「最初から君を 好きでいられて 良かった」なんて 空に歌うんだ
"I'm glad I was able to love you from the beginning," that's what I'll sing to the sky.
詰め込んだ夢を 打ち上げる場所
Seeking a place to launch the dreams I packed inside,
探し求めて この街から出た
I left this town.
震える着信 電源を切った
My phone vibrated, and I turned off the power.
燃え出す導火線 誰も止められない
My fuse is burning, and no one can stop it.
世界の終わりが 今訪れたとしたら
If the end of the world arrived right now,
人生の途中が
If the middle of life
線香花火だとしたら
were a sparkler,
一瞬でも ふたり照らす
lighting up the two of us even for a moment,
向日葵のように
like sunflowers,
Like a Fire Flower
いつか 夜空に大輪を 咲かすその時まで待ってくれ
waiting until the day a grand flower blooms in the night sky.
最初から君を 好きでいられて 良かったなって 空に歌うんだ
"I'm glad I was able to love you from the beginning," that's what I'll sing to the sky.
はい！裏切ったみんなー！
Yes! Everyone who betrayed me!
こんばんはー！どうも！
Good evening! Hello!
夏色まつりの清楚担当、
Natsuiro Matsuri, pure representative
みんなのアイドル夏色まつりでーす！
and everyone's idol!
ということで、今回のライブの
So, the title of this live
タイトルはですね、「夏色Fullbloom」でございます！
concert is "Natsuiro Fullbloom"!
あの、なんか季節色々みたいな
Uhm, apparently it has various
意味らしいです、調べたら。
seasonal meanings, I checked.
えーっと、夏春初秋のね、お花畑、
Uhm, for the flower fields of summer, spring, autumn...
ここにはいまひまわりが
sunflowers are blooming here
咲いてると思うんですけど、いいでしょ可愛いでしょう。
right now, aren't they cute?
はい、お花畑をテーマにですね、
Yes, with flower fields as the theme,
季節の移り変わりな感じでステージと、あの曲をいろいろ楽しんでもらえたらなと思いますよ。
enjoy the stage as seasons change.
はい！ということで、最初は
So, that first part was
夏のステージでございました。君と眺める夏の花火と、あと「Fire◎Flower」をね、聴いていただきましたけども、どうでしたか？
the summer stage. How was it?
よかった？ありがとうございます！
Was it good? Thank you!
どうよこのひまわりたち！
How are these sunflowers?
めっちゃ綺麗！すっごい咲いてるの、すっごい。
They're so pretty and blooming!
あの花火もね、上がっ、上がってたでしょ？ヒュって！
And those fireworks went up with a "whoosh"!
今も上がる？ヒュって！わあ、綺麗！
Are they going up now too? Wow, pretty!
もうね、ちょっと夏は終わってるんですけどもね、
Summer is already over in reality,
この世界では夏を楽しめるということで、季節自由自在でございます、バーチャルなのでな！
but here we can enjoy summer anytime.
これからもね、ちょっとまあ春とか秋とか冬とかも来ますので、
Spring, autumn, and winter will come too,
何の和が咲くのか予想しながら見ていただけたらなと思います。
so watch while guessing what flowers bloom.
そして、ライブの前にですね、あのダンスの練習動画もね投稿したと思うんですけど、
Before the live, I posted a dance practice video too,
見てくれましたか？
did you watch it?
今回ねダンスまた頑張ってますので、あのたくさん注目して見てくれると嬉しいなと思います！
I'm working hard on the dance again, so please watch!
メンバーまだ入ってないよって方は入ってくれると嬉しいなと思います。
If you haven't joined membership yet, I'd be happy if you did.
ということで、今回のライブの感想は
So please share your thoughts on
夏色フルブルームでたくさんつぶやいてください！夏色が漢字で、フルブルームが英語となっております。
today's live with "#NatsuiroFullbloom"!
ということで、次の季節がそろそろきそうですね？
So, the next season is almost here.
では行きますよ！次の季節へ、レッツゴー！
Here we go! To the next season, let's go!
ねぇ もう暗くなりそうだから
Hey, it's getting dark soon,
デチちゃってもいいかしら？
Is it okay if I head out?
ちょっとね 魔法にかけられた キミのお菓子から食べちゃうぞ
Just a bit—I was put under a spell, / I'm gonna eat your sweets first!
きっともう霧が濃くなるから ミンナ集まるかな？
Surely the fog will get thicker soon, / Will everyone gather around?
じっと待ってアマイモノ我慢した ご褒美をほら
Waiting patiently, resisting sweets— / Look at your reward!
ひとつ ふたつ 鐘の音 騒ぎ出す 小さいオバケたち
One, two, sound of the bells, / Little ghosts starting to make a fuss
今日は許してくれるの さあ街に行こう
Today they'll forgive us, / Now let's go into town!
だって Happy Halloween 悪戯しちゃうぞ ding-dong-dang
Because it's Happy Halloween, / We'll pull pranks, ding-dong-dang!
あっちもこっちも trick or treat キャンディーはくれないの？
Trick or treat here and there, / Won't you give me candy?
だって Happy Halloween 幼気な ランタン パンプキン
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Innocent lantern pumpkin,
疲れた ジャック も踊る よ朝 まで
Weary Jack dances too, until morning!
だって Happy Halloween オバケ の カブ だって ラララ
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Ghost's turnip, lalala!
今日 は 街中 trick or treat チョコ も 頂戴 よ
Today is trick or treat all over town, / Give me chocolate too!
だって Happy Halloween 不思議な世界 へようこそ 疲れた ジャック も歌う よ let's trick or treat
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Welcome to a mysterious world, weary Jack sings too, let's trick or treat
もっと もっと 欲しい 欲張り ゴースト
Wanting more and more, greedy ghost,
もう ない ？ それなら
None left? If so,
悪戯 の 餌食 ね くれた ない 家 なんて 庭木 に
You're prank bait! Houses that won't give us treats, on their garden trees
トイレットペーパー ぐるぐる し ちゃう お家 は ランタン 灯し て いる なら
We'll wrap toilet paper all around! / If you have your lantern lit,
甘い の 頂戴 さあ let's party night
Give us something sweet, come on, let's party night!
ほら だって Happy Halloween 時計 も回る tick-tack
Look, because it's Happy Halloween, / Clocks are spinning too, tick-tack,
あっちもこっちも trick or treat 目もくらむ パンプキンパイ
Trick or treat here and there, / Dazzling pumpkin pie!
だって Happy Halloween だだから 夜更かし しちゃう じぁ ない
Because it's Happy Halloween, / That's why we'll stay up late, right?
疲れた ジャック も寝ない わ 朝 まで
Weary Jack won't sleep either, until morning!
だって Happy Halloween だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Because it's Happy Halloween,
だって Happy Halloween 今日 は Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Today is Happy Halloween,
さあ let's trick or treat 赤い キャンディ コロ がして
Come on, let's trick or treat, / Rolling red candies around,
朝 まで 寝たく ない
I don't want to sleep until morning!
もっと もっと 欲しい 欲張り ゴースト
Wanting more and more, greedy ghost,
もう ない ？ それなら 悪戯 の 餌食 ね
None left? If so, you're prank bait!
くれた ない 家 なんて 庭木 に トイレットペーパー ぐるぐる し ちゃう
Houses that won't give us treats, / We'll wrap toilet paper all around their trees!
今夜 は ランタン 灯し て いる なら 甘い の 頂戴
If you have your lantern lit tonight, / Give us something sweet!
くれた ない 家 なんて 庭木 に トイレットペーパー ぐるぐる し ちゃう
Houses that won't give us treats, / We'll wrap toilet paper all around their trees!
今夜 は ランタン 灯し て いる なら 甘い の 頂戴
If you have your lantern lit tonight, / Give us something sweet!
さあ let's party night ほら だって Happy Halloween
Come on, let's party night, / Look, because it's Happy Halloween,
時計 も回る tick-tack あっちもこっちも trick or treat
Clocks spinning too, tick-tack, / Trick or treat here and there!
目もくらむ パンプキンパイ だって Happy Halloween
Dazzling pumpkin pie, / Because it's Happy Halloween,
だから 夜更かし しちゃう じぁ ない 疲れた ジャック も寝ない わ 朝 まで
That's why we'll stay up late, right? / Weary Jack won't sleep either, until morning!
だって Happy Halloween だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Because it's Happy Halloween,
だって Happy Halloween 今日 は Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Today is Happy Halloween,
さあ let's trick or treat 赤い キャンディ コロ がして
Come on, let's trick or treat, / Rolling red candies around,
朝 まで 寝たく ない だって Happy Halloween
I don't want to sleep until morning, / Because it's Happy Halloween!
だって Happy Halloween だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Because it's Happy Halloween,
だって Happy Halloween 今日 は Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween, / Today is Happy Halloween,
さあ let's trick or treat 赤い キャンディ コロ がして 朝 まで 寝たく ない
Come on, let's trick or treat, / Rolling red candies around, I don't want to sleep until morning!
今宵はHalloween Night!
Tonight is Halloween Night!
12時になり響いた 境界 気づけば通り過ぎてる
The boundary chimed at 12 o'clock, / Before we knew it, we passed right through.
見つけた まクマ不思議な招待 逃げたら足おきすりつ
We found a rather mysterious invitation, / If you run away, your feet will...
とびら開けたら まるで タイムマシーン！
When I open this door, it's like a time machine!
まきもどされた 夢のでぃずにっちっく
Rewound into a dream's discotheque
君をさがして あやしげなぱーてぃー
Searching for you at a suspicious party
おどりあかす あいのもんすたー
Monsters of love dancing the night away
みらーぼーるがまわる だんすふろーあ
The mirror ball spins over the dance floor
かそうぎょうれつ だれかのTrick or Treat
A costume parade, someone's Trick or Treat
ぼくはひとりでに とほうにくれてる
I'm all alone, completely at a loss
りずむのうず どうすればいいの？
Caught in the eddy of rhythm, what should I do?
Halloween night!
Midnight Boogie night!
かぼちゃがささやいている
Jack-o'-lanterns are whispering
さあ 手をたたけ! こしをふれ!
Come on, clap your hands! Shake your hips!
こんやはだれもばかになれ!
Tonight, anyone can be a fool!
Halloween night! さあ おどれ!
Halloween night! Come on, dance!
ことばはいらないよ
You don't need any words
もう いやなことわすれよう!
Forget all the unpleasant things already!
ねんにいちどのかーにばる
A carnival once a year
きょうだけじゆうなおばけたち
Ghosts are free just for today
Halloween night!
さあみんなでみんなでみんなでおどろ
Come on, everyone, let's dance together!
たったりたりな ねたんしないでおどろ
Dancing without getting sleepy, let's dance
おかしをもっとちょうだいちょーだい
Give me more sweets, give me more
すきにやりたいように
Do whatever you like
おつかいのそらをとぼう
Let's fly across the sky of errands
しめいたちもおどれ
Fulfillments, dance too
いまから始まるぱりーはろういんない!
Now starting, Party Halloween Night!
Crazy night!
まだまだ ほらおかしなしょうたい
Still, look, a strange invitation
つづきは よみのよなかで
The continuation is in the dead of night
きづけば もうにどと戻れない
Before you know it, you can never go back
あくもんで 狼男もわらう
At the nightmare, even the werewolf laughs
それじゃ全然なってない 君はまっさかさまじゃんふぉーりんらぶ
That's totally wrong, you've fallen head over heels!
みんな おかしの準備はできてたよね？
Everyone, you're ready with your sweets, right?
もってないひとには いたずらしちゃうからね!
If you don't have any, I'll play a trick on you!
おかしの準備ができたひとから手をあげて
Those who are ready with sweets, raise your hands!
おかしなくちゃ はずしてほしいのかな？ たべちゃうぞ!
Without sweets, do you want me to take it off? I'll eat you up!
さあ だいないと ほらもっと
Come on, dance night, look, even more
ていしなんて きょうははろういん
Stop? No way, today is Halloween
つきり とびのるように
As if leaping onto the moon
おばちゃんのり にのってしゅっこうよ
Hop on the goblin ride and set sail!
でもきしもの ってれとろ
Even knightly things are retro
ちゃみのも みのも みのも おどろ
Dance, everyone, everyone, everyone!
ざっぱりたりな
Zappari tarina...
ばんざいないとじゃおどろ
Dance on Banzai Night!
よぼう ともおどるわ
Even prevention dances
にんげんたちも ほらほら かおも
Humans too, look, look, face as well
べつのせかい そろいよおどろうか
Shall we gather and dance in another world?
まだおわらない たりたりなる
It's not over yet, tari tari naru
そう ころにらわれた ぼくらの
Yes, captured in this night, our...
おうな いぱーてぃー
Grand party!
ああ まったくはじまる ばりーはろういんない!
Ah, it's starting at last, Party Halloween Night!
クレイジーナイト!
Crazy Night!
ああ…
Ah...
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, Mr. Mirror
世界で一番可愛いのは やめてよ
Stop asking who's the fairest in the world!
棘のような視線迫る 優しフリした彼女が
Stares like thorns close in, as she pretends to be kind
素敵な晩餐もてなした
Serving a wonderful dinner
そっと 口に含むと [笑み]
As I gently take a bite into my mouth...
薄れゆく 意思の中で
Amidst my fading consciousness,
夢を見ている いつかのおとぎ話 時が止まる
I dream of a fairy tale from long ago, where time stops.
お願い kiss で目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
So you can carry me out of this white casket.
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマ的な事情
Piercing hatred is just a dramatic circumstance,
祈っても 王子様はまだ来ない
Even though I pray, my prince still hasn't come.
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, Mr. Mirror...
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, oh mirror, oh mirror,
ネクタイ任せ 頬に挨拶するから
leaving it to your necktie, greeting my cheeks,
妬みを買われてしまった
I've gone and incurred their jealousy.
7人の小人はいるけど
There are seven dwarves around,
助ける素振り 知らんふりね
but they act like they know nothing, pretending not to help.
そっと首を掴まれ
Gently having my neck grabbed...
笑み
A smile...
一粒の
Even a single teardrop
涙さえも 拭えなくて
couldn't be wiped away,
呼吸もままならない
breathing is uncontrollable,
視界失せた
my vision has failed.
消えそうだから 早く駆けて欲しいの
I'm about to fade away, so I want you to run to me quickly.
訳は聞かないで
Don't ask me why,
応えられない
I can't answer.
望まない 憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love.
もうすぐで いなくなるのかな
Will I be disappearing very soon?
途切れてく
Fading away,
命の音
the sound of life.
毒リンゴを食した少女のように
Like a girl who ate a poisoned apple,
眠りにつく
falling into sleep.
お願いKISSで 目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
胸の中の声 届きますか
does the voice in my heart reach you?
階段を上ったら ドアを開けるだけで
If you climb the stairs and just open the door,
見つかるよ
you'll find me.
あー
Ah...
お願いKISSで 目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
白い棺から 連れ出すように
as if leading me out of a white coffin,
突き刺さる 憎しみは ドラマ的な事情
piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance.
昨日の今日も 君はまだ来ない
Yesterday and today, you still haven't come.
消えてしまう
Before I fade away
その前に
before that...
「ねえ こっちおいでよ…なんて」
"Hey, come closer here... just kidding"
「えーっと 聞いてますよ…なんて」
"Umm, I can hear you... just kidding"
1, 2, 3, 4!
「もう冬ですね」
"It's already winter"
「そうクリスマス」
"Yeah, Christmas"
「どこか行きたい？」
"Where do you want to go?"
「部屋でもいいよ」
"We can just stay in the room"
「みんな呼ぼうか？」
"Should we call everyone?"
「二人きりがいいのに…」
"I wanted us to be alone..."
「冗談だよ、そのつもり」
"Just kidding, I meant that"
「もー！」
"Hey!"
「予約したんだ」
"I made a reservation"
「わーオシャレなお店！」
"Wow, what a stylish restaurant!"
「…落ち着かないな」
"...I can't seem to calm down"
「無理しちゃったね」
"You pushed yourself, huh"
「何頼もうか？」
"What should we order?"
「メニューが読めないです」
"I can't read the menu"
大人になれますか？
Can we truly become adults?
雪景色 東京タワー
Tokyo Tower illuminated by snow,
君の目が潤んでいる
your eyes are tearing up.
ライトアップが二人の影 想いを近づけた
The lights brought our shadows and feelings closer.
please please こっちおいでよ
Please please come closer,
アゲてここう hey dj! party k night!
raise your energy, hey DJ! Party K Night!
寂しいなんて言わせない
Won't let you say you're lonely,
嫌なことは bye!
say bye to things you hate!
騒ごう
Let's party!
大好きな人と踊ろう
Dance with the one you love most,
大胆なことしちゃおう
let's do something bold.
急接近 上目づかい
Sudden close-up, looking up,
今日こそと思ってたのに ah…
even though I thought today's the day, ah...
「新年ですね」
"It's the new year"
「そうバレンタイン」
"Yeah, Valentine's"
「ちょ、早いない？」
"Wait, isn't that too early?"
「予行練習！」
"Rehearsal!"
「…必要かもね」
"...Maybe necessary"
「今年こそは完食」
"This year I'll finish it all"
「目指して頑張ります！おー！」
"Let's do our best! Yeah!"
「初詣とか」
"Visiting the shrine"
「人が多いね」
"There are so many people"
「お願いは何？」
"What was your wish?"
「えー、秘密だよ」
"Um, it's a secret"
「おみくじなんて」
"Fortune slips"
「気にしなくていいのに」
"You don't need to mind them"
「気合が入ります」
"Gets me motivated"
君とはじめての朝 初日の出 染まる君
The first morning with you, you're dyed in the sunrise,
オレンジ色 輝いて
glowing in an orange hue.
ねえ ねえ 触れてたいよ
Hey, hey, I want to touch you.
dance dance こっちおいでよ
Dance dance, come closer,
揺らしてよ dj! party k night!
shake it up, DJ! Party K Night!
このままじゃ終わない
It won't end like this,
今だけの chance!
chance of a lifetime!
話そう
Let's talk!
明日のことは忘れよう
Let's forget about tomorrow,
今じゃなくちゃだめなんです
it has to be right now.
急展開も楽しもう
Let's enjoy this rapid development.
今日こそは君に…「好きだよ」
Today's the day I'll tell you "I love you".
oh oh oh…
Oh oh oh...
「君じゃなくちゃだめなんです」
"You're the only one for me"
please please こっちおいでよ
Please please come closer,
アゲてここう hey dj! party k night!
raise your energy, hey DJ! Party K Night!
寂しいなんて言わせない
Won't let you say you're lonely,
嫌なことは bye!
say bye to things you hate!
騒ごう
Let's party!
大好きな人と踊ろう
Dance with the one you love most,
大胆なことしちゃおう
let's do something bold.
急接近 上目づかい
Sudden close-up, looking up,
今日こそは君に伝える「好きだよ」
today's the day I'll tell you "I love you".
「ねえ こっちおいでよ …なんて」
"Hey, come closer here... just kidding"
「えーっと 聞いてますよ …なんて」
"Umm, I can hear you... just kidding"
1, 2, 3, 4!
「もう冬ですね」
"It's already winter,"
「そうクリスマス」
"that's right, Christmas."
「どこか行きたい？」
"Where do you want to go?"
「部屋でもいいよ」
"My room is fine too."
「みんな呼ぼうか？」
"Should we call everyone?"
「二人きりがいいのに…」
"Even though I wanted us alone..."
「冗談だよ、そのつもり」
"Just kidding, that's the plan."
「もー！」
"Hey!"
「予約したんだ」
"I made a reservation."
「わー オシャレなお店！」
"Whoa, what a stylish place!"
･･･落ち着かない
"...I can't calm down."
無理しちゃったね
"We pushed our luck, didn't we?"
何頼もうか？
"What should we order?"
メニューが読めないです
"I can't read the menu..."
大人になれますか？
"Can we truly become adults?"
雪景色東京タワー
"Tokyo Tower in the snowy scenery,"
君の目が潤んでいる
"Your eyes are welling up."
ライトアップが二人の
"The lights bring"
影想いを近づけた
"Our reflections closer together."
please please こっちおいでよ
"Please, please, come over here"
アゲてこ hey dj! party “k” night!
"Turn it up, hey DJ! Party “K” night!"
寂しいなんて言わせない
"I won't let you say you're lonely,"
やなことは bye!
"Say bye to all the bad things!"
騒ごう
"Let's party!"
大好きな人と踊ろう
"Dance with the one you love most,"
大胆なことしちゃおう
"And let's do something bold."
急接近上目づかい
"A sudden close-up, looking up from below—"
今日こそと思ってたのに ah..
"I thought today's the day, ah..."
「新年ですね」
"It's the New Year."
「そうバレンタイン」
"That's right, Valentine's."
「ちょ、早いくない？」
"Wait, isn't that too early?"
「予行練習！」
"A rehearsal!"
「…必要かもね」
"...Maybe that's necessary."
「今年こそは完食」
"This year we'll finish it all!"
「目指して頑張ります！おー！」
"Let's do our best! Oh!"
「初詣とか」
"Going to the shrine..."
「人が多いね」
"There are so many people."
「お祈りは何？」
"What did you wish for?"
「ええ、秘密だよ」
"Um, it's a secret."
「おみくじなんて」
"Even though fortunes..."
「気にしなくていいのにさ」
"Don't really matter much..."
「気合が入ります」
"I'm getting pumped up."
君とはじめての朝
"The first morning with you,"
初日の出染まる君
"You tinted by the first sunrise."
オレンジ色輝いて
"Glowing in an orange hue,"
ねぇねえ 触れていたいの
"Hey, hey, I want to touch you."
dance dance こっちおいでよ
"Dance, dance, come over here"
揺らし立てよ dj! party “k” night!
"Shake it up, hey DJ! Party “K” night!"
このままじゃ終えられない
"We can't let it end like this,"
今だけのチャンス！
"It's a once-in-a-lifetime chance!"
話そう
"Let's talk"
明日のことは忘れよう
"Let's forget about tomorrow,"
今じゃなくちゃダメなんです
"It has to be right now."
急展開も楽しもう
"Let's enjoy this sudden turn of events,"
今日こそは君に…
"Today's the day I'll tell you..."
「すきだよ」
"I love you."
「きみじゃなきゃダメなんです」
"It has to be you."
please please こっちおいでよ
"Please, please, come over here"
アゲてこ hey dj! party “k” night!
"Turn it up, hey DJ! Party “K” night!"
寂しいなんて言わせない
"I won't let you say you're lonely,"
やなことは bye!
"Say bye to all the bad things!"
騒ごう
"Let's party!"
大好きな人と踊ろう
"Dance with the one you love most,"
大胆なことしちゃおう
"And let's do something bold."
急接近上目づかい
"A sudden close-up, looking up from below—"
今日こそは君に伝える
"Today's the day I'll tell you,"
「すきだよ」
"I love you."
「きみじゃなきゃダメなんです」
"It has to be you."
please please こっちおいでよ
"Please, please, come over here"
上げてこう hey dj! party “k” night!
"Raise the roof, hey DJ! Party “K” night!"
寂しいなんて
"I won't let you say"
言わせない
"you're lonely,"
やなことは bye!
"Say bye to all the bad things!"
騒ごう
"Let's party!"
大好きな人と踊ろう
"Dance with the one you love most,"
大胆なことしちゃおう
"And let's do something bold."
急接近上目づかい
"A sudden close-up, looking up from below—"
今日こそは君に伝える
"Today's the day I'll tell you,"
「すきだよ」
"I love you."
大好きな人と踊ろう
"Dance with the one you love most,"
大胆なこと踊ろう
"And dance in a bold way."
大胆なことしちゃうわ
"Let's do something really bold!"
永久セッションは
"An eternal session is"
水着じゃない
"not a swimsuit,"
伝える
"I'll convey it."
「すきだよ」
"I love you."
YEAH!
ロマンティック 恋のアンテナは 嵐で何処へ飛んでいった
"Romantic, my love's antenna got blown away by a storm."
嘘でしょう 冷たくあしらった
"Can't be, I treated you so coldly."
こしゃくなエクボに ちょっと 心が揺れてる
"My heart is shaking a bit at your cheeky dimples."
ホントは 本気でアタシを 叱ってくれる大事なひと
"Actually, you're precious because you genuinely scold me."
…なんて言ったらアイツは 得意気にするから
"...If I said that, you'd look so smug,"
もう褒めたりしない
"so no more compliments from me!"
退屈な運命に 飽き飽きしたの
"I'm so sick and tired of this boring destiny."
知らない台詞で 解き放してね
"Free me with words I've never heard before, okay?"
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 壊してよ
"Darling, darling, break down the door to my heart!"
たいせつなことは 瞳を見て 曇らずに
"Look into my eyes clearly and tell me what's important,"
あなたとなら この街を抜け出せる
"With you, I can escape from this town."
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
"Take me away right now, My Sweet Sweet Darling!"
ドラマティック 笑顔の秘密を だれだって探し続けてる
"Dramatic, everyone keeps searching for the secret of a smile."
見上げた 空に描くのは 幸せのかたち
"What I draw in the sky above is the shape of happiness."
そう あたらしくいたい
"Yes, I want to stay fresh and new."
気まぐれなテンションで 振り回すけど
"I might swing you around with my moody tension,"
この手はかならず 離さないでね
"But never let go of this hand, okay?"
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 叩いてよ
"Darling, darling, knock on the door to my heart!"
素直な気持ちが あふれていく
"My honest feelings are overflowing."
あなたとなら 笑っていられるよ
"With you, I can keep smiling."
今すぐ 駆け出すの My Sweet Sweet Darling
"Running off right now, My Sweet Sweet Darling!"
ダーリン ダーリン きっと アタシ は つかまえる よ
"Darling, darling, I'll definitely capture you!"
幸せの意味に 気づいていく
"Realizing the true meaning of happiness."
あなたとなら 明日を変えられる
"With you, I can change tomorrow."
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
"Take me away right now, My Sweet Sweet Darling!"
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 壊してよ
"Darling, darling, break down the door to my heart!"
たいせつなことは 瞳を見て 曇らずに
"Look into my eyes clearly and tell me what's important,"
あなたとなら この街を抜け出せる
"With you, I can escape from this town."
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
"Take me away right now, My Sweet Sweet Darling!"
ロマンティック 笑顔の秘密を
"Romantic, the secret of a smile..."
だれだって探し続けてる
"Everyone keeps searching for it."
見上げた 空に描くのは
"What I draw in the sky above..."
幸せのかたち そう
"Is the shape of happiness, yes."
あたらしくいたい
"I want to stay fresh and new."
気まぐれなテンションで
"With a moody tension"
振り回すけど
"I might swing you around."
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
"Take me away right now, My Sweet Sweet Darling!"
ロマンティック 恋のアンテナは
Romantic, my love's antenna got
嵐で何処かへ飛んでいってた
blown away by a storm.
嘘でしょう 冷たく遇らった
That can't be, I treated him like ice.
こしょうくなエクボに ちょっと 心が揺れてる
My heart is shaking at his brazen dimples.
ホントは 本気であたしを 怒ってくれる大事なひと
Actually, I love when he gets serious and scolds me.
…なんて言ったらアイツは 得意気にするから もう褒めたりしない
But if I said so, he'd get proud, so no more compliments.
タイクツな運命に 飽き飽きしたの
I'm tired of this boring destiny.
知らない台詞で 解き放して ねぇ
Free me with words I've never heard before, okay?
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 壊してよ
Darling, darling, break down the door to my heart!
まいすいーと すいーたーい あい
Take me away now, my sweet sweet darling!
ダーリン ダーリン きっと あたしは つかめるよ
Darling, darling, I know you can capture me.
幸せの意味に 気づいていくんだ
I'm realizing what happiness is.
あなたとならば 明日を変えられるよ
I can see a new tomorrow together with you.
いますぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
Take me away now, my sweet sweet darling!
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 壊してよ
Darling, darling, break down the door to my heart!
まいすいーと すいーたーい あい
Take me away now, my sweet sweet darling!
ドラマティック 笑顔の秘密を だれだって探し続けてる
Dramatic, everyone keeps searching for the secret of smiles.
見上げた 空に描くの 幸せのかたち
I'll draw happiness in the sky above.
そう あたしらしくいたい
Yes, I want to be true to myself.
気まぐれなテンションで 振りまわすけど
I'll spin you round with bold tension,
この手はかならず 離さないで ねぇ
but don't let go of my hand, okay?
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を 叩いてよ
Darling, darling, knock on the door to my heart!
素直な気持ちが あふれていく
I can feel my honest emotions welling up.
あなたとならば 笑っていられるよ
I can see myself laughing together with you.
いますぐ 駆け出すの My Sweet Sweet Darling
We're taking off right now, my sweet sweet darling!
探しに行くんだ そこへ
I'll head over there to search...
そこへ
Over there...
探しに行くんだ そこへ
I'll head over there to search...
空隙を埋め 完了した定理
The theory I completed to fill this space
正しい筈なのに
should be correct, but
ひらりひらり からまわる
it spins gently and aimlessly around.
未来は歪で
The future is chaotic...
僅かな亀裂から いくらでも綻んで
from the slightest crack it diverges
理想から逸れていくんだ
and strays from the ideal.
ぬるま湯が すっと冷めていく音がしてた
The lukewarm water began to cool down.
道を変えるのなら 今なんだ
If you're going to change paths, now is the time.
こんなレプリカは いらない
I don't want this replica;
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
I only want what's real.
探しに行くんだ そこへ
I'll head over there to search...
「でもそれは よくできたフェアリーテイルみたい。」
"That's like a fairy tale."
答えの消えた 空隙を見つめる
I gaze at the empty space where my answer disappeared.
埋めた筈なのに どうしても解らない
It should be filled, but I can't tell.
綺麗な花は 大事に育てても
Even if you raise a flower with care,
遠慮ない土足で 簡単に踏み蹂虪された
it's easily trampled by muddy shoes.
降り積もる白に 小さな芽覆われていく
A small sprout is covered by the white snow.
遠い遠い春は 雪の下
Far, far away, spring is under the snow.
見えないものは どうしても記憶から薄れてしまうんだ
Unseen things fade from memory.
探しに行く場所さえも 見失う僕たちは 気付かず芽を踏む
We step on the sprout without noticing.
思い出を頼りに創ってた花はすぐ枯れた
The flowers made from memory withered away.
足元には気付かずに 本物と呼べる場所を
Without noticing what was at our feet...
探しに行くのは きっと 今なんだ
Surely, now is the time to search for the real deal.
こんなレプリカは いらない
I don't want this replica;
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
I only want what's real.
探しに行くから 君を
I'll head over there to search for you...
「ありがとう 小さな芽見つけてくれたこと。」
"Thank you for finding this small sprout for me."
君はつぶやいた
You whispered.
本物と呼べる場所を
A place that can be called the real thing
探しに行くんだ そこへきっと
I'll go search for it there, for sure
今なんだ
Now's the time
こんなレプリカはいらない
I don't need a replica like this
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
Only something I can call the real thing is fine
探しに行くから 君を
Because I'm going to search for you
ありがとう 小さな芽
Thank you, tiny sprout
見つけてくれたこと
For finding me
君はつぶやいた
You whispered
一日百時間くらいあればいいのにな
I wish we had about 100 hours in a day
やり残したことたくさんでカバンが満杯
With so much left undone, my bag is overflowing
君をわかりたい
I want to understand you
君を忘れたい
I want to forget you
君を守りたい
I want to protect you
それぞれの願い
Each of our wishes
海の家 山の家 故郷の家
Beach house, mountain house, hometown house
世界中悠々夏休みカーニバル
A leisurely summer vacation carnival all over the world
お天道様のご機嫌で一身上の都合で
At the sun's pleasure and for personal reasons
潜る思い出 誰一人影川を遡れ
Diving into memories, swimming upstream against time
弾む息継ぎ 仲間の声
Breathless breaths, the voices of our friends
終わるじゃない この数秒と泳いだ影
It's not ending, this shadow we swam with for these few seconds
大丈夫 どんな結末だってきっと全て夏が終えて
It's alright, no matter what the ending is, summer will finish everything
あまりに早くおとなになりたがったどり
We were in such a hurry to grow up
そうだろう 分からないよ
Is that so? I don't know
永遠の夏休み さよならだって
Eternal summer vacation, even if it's goodbye
数週間きらめき まだ続く物語
A few weeks of sparkle, a story that still continues
まだ泣くなよさあ あどけないままで
Don't cry yet, come on, stay innocent
3年待ち焦がれて 飛び出したお祭り
Yearning for three years, the festival we dashed out into
静けさに溶けて 夏に焦がれた
Melting into the silence, yearning for summer
僕らの夏休みはサマーバケーション
Our summer vacation is a summer vacation
海の家 山の家 故郷の家
Beach house, mountain house, hometown house
世界中悠々夏休みカーニバル
A leisurely summer vacation carnival all over the world
僕が好きな君が好きな奴は誰が好きなんだ一体関係
Who does the person I like, who likes you, actually like? Such a complicated relationship!
あれあれ何でステージ立って待ってなんで
Huh? Why am I standing on stage waiting? Why?
我れ先光り合う運命まで遠い僕らの踏み台も
Even our stepping stones to a shining destiny are still far away
また時が巡れば思い出すよ
When time comes around again, I'll remember
あの青と青の境界線は錆びから覗いた白い雲を
The boundary line of blue and blue, looking through the rust at the white clouds
来年も再来年も笑って泣いてみたいな
I want to laugh and cry again next year and the year after
お前も、お前も、君も大好きだ
You too, you too, I love you all!
永遠の夏休み 花火だなんて
Eternal summer vacation, calling it fireworks
瞬きだんだんきらめき 命も役回り
Blinking, sparkling gradually, life's role as well
まだ泣くなよさあ 学生服だって
Don't cry yet, come on, even school uniforms
3年かまい育ち 欲しい上の片隅
Raised for three years, in the corner of what we desired
共にごいま この川 僕だろう
Together now, this river, must be me
本当はみんな 気づかぬふりしてた この夏には
Actually, everyone was pretending not to notice that this summer
もう二度と戻れないってこと
We could never return to it again
一日百時間くらいあればいいのにな
I wish we had about 100 hours in a day
やり残したことたくさんでカバンが満杯
With so much left undone, my bag is overflowing
君を流せない
I can't let you flow away
君を忘れない
I won't forget you
君を話さない
I won't let go of you
それぞれの近い
Each of our vows
沈む日と共に 水平線に隠した
Hidden on the horizon along with the setting sun
僕らの夏はサマーバケーション
Our summer is a summer vacation
永遠の夏休み 夏休みだって
Eternal summer vacation, even in summer vacation
数週間きらめき まだ続くものか
A few weeks of sparkle, something still continuing
まだ泣くなよさあ バブルゼミだって
Don't cry yet, come on, even cicadas in a bubble
3年まちこがれて
Yearning for three years
飛び出したお祭り
The festival we dashed out into
永遠の夏休み 永遠の夏
Eternal summer vacation, eternal summer
まだ泣くなよさあ まだ泣くなよ
Don't cry yet, come on, don't cry yet
静けさに溶けて 夏にこだました
Melting into the silence, echoing into summer
僕らの夏はサマーバケーション
Our summer is a summer vacation
というわけで、ありえないほどっ！消し忘れちゃったよっ、ただいまーっ！
And with that, I completely forgot to turn it off! I'm back!
はいっ、今回ですね、夏に始まり、夏で終わる、ちょっとストーリー感のあるセットリストにしてみましたけど、どうでしたか？可愛かった？
Yes! So this time, I made a setlist with a bit of a story-like feel that starts in summer and ends in summer. How was it? Was it cute?
うわ、ありがとね！ゲストパートもね、もうみんな一緒に歌ってくれて嬉しかったでございますよっ！
Wow, thank you so much! I was so happy that everyone sang along during the guest part too!
ちなみに、この配信が終わったあとにメンバー限定のね、あの、アンコールライブもありますので、ぜひぜひ見に来てくださいね！
By the way, right after this stream ends, there's also a member-only, um, encore live, so please make sure to come check it out!
ラストもね、あの、本編頑張っておりますので、ちょっと、あの、感想とかもたくさんつ、えー、ポストをしてください！はいっ！
Also, for the last part, um, we worked really hard on the main show, so please, um, post lots of your impressions and thoughts! Yes!
そして、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまいます！早いねっ！
And, believe it or not, the next song will be the last one! Time flies, huh?
はいっ、最後はなんと新曲でございまぁす！やったーッ！はい、ということで、
Yes, and the final song is brand new! Yay! So,
え、タイトルは、こちら！ばばーん、こっち！「ENDLESS FES」でございますっ！
um, the title is right here! Ta-da, right here! "ENDLESS FES"!
え、作詞はですね、みんな大好きFAKE TYPE.さんにお願いをしましたよっ！そしてMV制作はPPPさんでございますっ！
Um, the lyrics were done by everyone's favorite FAKE TYPE.-san! And the MV production was done by PPP-san!
え、このあと、え、11月1日の24時にね、リリースされますので、無限に聞いてください！もう無限に聞きたくなる中毒性のある曲でございます！なんか、あの、祭りさが超リアルなリスになっているのは、ちょっとMVで見てみてね！ふふっ！
Um, after this, um, it will be released at midnight on November 1st, so please listen to it endlessly! It's a dangerously addictive song that you'll want to listen to endlessly! And well, the festival-like super realistic squirrels—check them out in the MV! Hehe!
はいっ！そしてMV公開は、この配信のあとにプレミア公開がありますので、そちらもお見逃しなく！よろしくうぇけわんつー！
Yes! And the MV premiere will happen right after this stream, so don't miss that either! Thank you—one, two!
はい、ということで、それでは聞いてください、「ENDLESS FES」！
Yes, with that, please listen to "ENDLESS FES"!
天を衝いた神輿
A sacred palanquin piercing the heavens,
フェスティバルルンルン 奉り候
Festival run-run, paying homage!
文明開化のお通りです 今日も今日とてぁしは上機嫌
Making way for civilization, today as well I'm in high spirits!
Let's party, don't panic こっちおいで電脳ジャンキー
Let's party, don't panic, come over here, cyber junkie!
Wifi 可視化でわいわいはしゃげば 曖昧なことは大体 Whatever
Making Wi-Fi visible and making noise, vague things are mostly Whatever!
接続完了でハイテンション
Connection complete, high tension!
えんやこら上がれ 総員パワー合わせ
Heave-ho, rise up, all hands combine your power!
銀河すら凌駕する輝きを
A brilliance that surpasses even the galaxy,
ほら一丁鳴らせ おまけにもういっちょ鳴らせ
Look, ring it once, and ring it once more for good measure!
カルチャーごちゃ混ぜの万華鏡は
A kaleidoscope mixed with all sorts of cultures is
鳴呼 絶景かな
Ah, what a breathtaking view!
相変わらず連縁と畳縁
Still the same endless connections and tatami edges,
ミームはまるで花火の如し
Memes are just like fireworks,
鮮やかに咲き乱れては刻まれる
Blooming brilliantly and getting etched into history!
超超超超現象巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Whip up a super-duper mega phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないいないボイ
No ifs and buts, there's none at all, boy!
滾々混沌でも舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Dance wildly even in churning chaos (Yeah!)
ないものないエンターテインメント
Entertainment with nothing lacking,
飛び跳ねろ
Jump and leap!
とりあえず朝まで 昼夜問わず繋がっちゃおう
For now, let's connect until morning, day or night!
Oh bounce... baby bounce
感覚サマーバケーションみたいでしょ？とびきりの Fun time
Feeling like a summer vacation, aren't you? With a supreme fun time!
今日もいつもの場所から始まる Superb view
Starting today from the usual place, a superb view!
Look at you 選び取り見取りで供給過多気味
Look at you, picking and choosing with an oversupply,
But you said "Give me give me" It's a part of 生きる意味
But you said "Give me give me" It's a part of the meaning of life!
オレンジ色マーマレード 太陽のような笑え
Orange marmalade, smile like the sun!
宇宙すら越え遥か彼方にも
Reaching far beyond even the universe,
ほら一丁かませ おまけにもういっちょかませ
Look, tackle it once, and tackle it once more for good measure!
ジャンルごちゃ混ぜの Turntable
A genre-mixed turntable,
鳴呼 絶景かな
Ah, what a breathtaking view!
予測出来ない展開なハート
A heart with unpredictable developments,
みんなの心を静かに 華やかに伝播されてハート満たされる
Quietly and brilliantly transmitting everyone's hearts to fill them up!
超超超超現象巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Whip up a super-duper mega phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないいないボイ
No ifs and buts, there's none at all, boy!
滾々混沌でも舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Dance wildly even in churning chaos (Yeah!)
ないものないエンターテインメント
Entertainment with nothing lacking,
飛び跳ねろ
Jump and leap!
天を衝いた神輿 フェスティバルルンルン 奉り候
A sacred palanquin piercing the heavens, festival run-run, paying homage!
勉強も遊びも On the web 気勢に集まり
Studies and play alike, gathering eagerly on the web!
勉強も遊びも On the web 気楽に集まり
Whether studying or playing, gathering casually on the web,
国境越えてコラボレート ピースに交わり
Crossing borders to collaborate, mingling in peace,
好きなデバイスでご覧あれ 湧きたつ勇気溌剌
Watch on your favorite device, surging with vibrant courage,
もう立派なネット中毒です あとのまつり (My men)
You're already a full-blown net addict, it's Matsuri's festival (My men)!
超超超超現象巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Stir up a super-super-super-super phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないないボイ
There's no such thing as "what ifs," no way, boy!
波々混沌でも舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Even in raging chaos, dance around (Yeah!)
なんでもありエンターテインメント エンドレスのフェス
Anything goes entertainment, an endless festival!
兎にも角にも目一杯楽しんでね
In any case, enjoy yourself to the fullest!